Guide to the Duke University Museum of Art Reference Collection, 1932 - 2001 UA.01.11.0008
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University Museum of Art Reference collection
1932 - 2001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. University Archives
UA.01.11.0008
1 Linear Feet
The Duke University Museum of Art Reference Collection contains clippings, exhibit catalogs, articles, flyers, and other material about the Duke University Museum of Art and the Nasher Museum of Art at Duke University. These files were compiled from a variety of sources by University Archives staff for use in reference and research. English.
1000 Items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
No restrictions.
Provenance
The Duke University Museum of Art Reference Collection was compiled by the University Archives from a variety of sources.
Historical Note
From 1930 to 1969, the Woman's College Library (now the Lilly Library) on East Campus was the principal venue for art exhibits at Duke. In 1969, Duke University opened an art museum in the renovated science building on East Campus. In 1998, alumnus Raymond D. Nasher donated funds to support construction of a new art museum at Duke University, the Nasher Museum of Art, which opened in 2005.
Collection Overview
The Duke University Museum of Art Reference Collection contains clippings, exhibit catalogs, a docents' manual, articles, flyers, and other materials about the Duke University Museum of Art, and later the Nasher Museum of Art at Duke University.
Related Material
Museum of Art Records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Art Association Records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Art -- North Carolina -- Durham -- Catalogs; Art museums -- North Carolina -- Durham; Exhibition catalogs; Clippings (information artifacts); Nasher Museum of Art at Duke University; Duke University. Museum of Art; Duke University. University Archives
- Folder list
  - Brummer Collection (Box 1)
  - Exhibit catalogs (Box 1)
  - Exhibit catalog: Reiner/Tinari, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Exhibits, 1932, 1967-1989 (Box 1)
  - Exhibits, 1990-2000 (Box 1)
  - Exhibits, 2000- (Box 1)
  - Friends of the Duke University Museum of Art (Box 1)
  - Spencer, John. Who needs an Art Museum anyhow? Duke University Letters. No. 56: Jan 11 1984 (Box 1)
  - History (Box 1)
  - Mary and Jim Semans Lectureship Series, 1997- (Box 1)
  - Newsletter, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1980s (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, 2000- (Box 1)
  - Rental program (Box 1)
  - Duke University Museum of Art Docents' Manual (in binder), circa 1996-1997 (Box 2)